I'm here to discuss short curly locks with you.
The tools that you're going to want to use to create a curl can consist of thermal styling tools which is ultimately your curling iron.
Curling irons come in various diameters they come very small, 1/2" they go to 3/4", the 1" 1 1/2" and then the 2".
The longer the larger the diameter the looser the weight is going to be.
Now when somebody like Heather's hair, you also must take into consideration the length of her hair.
If I was to use this on this section, it would only do one turn, it would be very very loose and it would literally use something like this on shorter hair just to kind to give it a little bevel around the face.
Just to really kind to get the hair to either go under or flip out, the smaller diameter will work best on her hair.
Another great benefit with curling irons such as this one is does have a heat adjustment on it.
The heat adjustment will allow for you to adjust the heat to order to cater to your hair.
Now Heather has very fine hair and this goes to extra hot.
She's not going to need something extra hot in order to go on her hair so you can actually bring it down to maybe your highs speed or high temperature.
The courser your hair is, the hotter the most you would likely need your thermal styling tool to be in order to really work on your hair.
Now if I grab this, the softer the curl is the better it would be especially you can see when they're going to fall.
So you can see that the curl is very tight, very wiggly.
That is what you want when you're working with shorter hair especially fine and straight hair.
It's going to help achieve your style and it's going to help you maintain your movement maintaining your curl and also add some volume.